欢迎回来。
Welcome back.
在本次讲座中，
In this lecture,
我们将学习如何在 CSS 中使用颜色。
we will learn how to work with colors in CSS.
然而，在我们真正回到我们的 CSS 之前，
However, before we can actually go back to our CSS,
我们首先需要了解一点理论
we first need to learn a little bit about the theory
如何使用代码表示颜色。
of how to represent colors using code.
现在，有很多表示颜色的方法
Now, there are many ways of representing colors
在计算机中，基本上是在编写代码中，
in computers and basically in writing code,
但更传统的模型之一是 RGB 模型。
but one of the more traditional models is the RGB model.
所以在 RGB 模型中，
So in the RGB model,
每一种颜色都可以表示
every single color can be represented
通过红色、绿色和蓝色的任意组合。
by any combination of red, green, and blue colors.
所以看起来像这样。
So that looks something like this.
也许你已经看过这样的图表
And maybe you have already seen a diagram like this
在学校的某个地方或类似的地方。
somewhere in school or something like that.
所以无论如何，为了真正代表某种颜色，
So anyway, in order to actually represent a certain color,
我们需要给出三种基本颜色中的每一种，
we need to give each of the three base colors,
0 到 255 之间的任何值。
any value between zero and 255.
就这样，
And so with that,
我们总共可以定义 1680 万种不同的颜色。
we can define a total of 16.8 million different colors.
所以让我们用这里的图表稍微理解一下
So let's understand this a little bit using our diagram here
从纯红色开始。
and starting with the pure red color.
当然，在这个通道中，红色是最大的，
Of course, in this channel, red is at the complete maximum,
这是255和其他两个通道。
which is 255 and the other two channels.
所以其他两种基色为零。
So the other two base colors are at zero.
所以没有任何绿色，也没有任何蓝色。
So there is no green whatsoever and no blue whatsoever.
这就是为什么它是纯红色的。
And so this is why this is pure red.
再说一次，
So again,
红色通道处于最大值
the red channel is at the maximum value
而所有其他的都为零。
and all the other ones are at zero.
当然，蓝色和绿色也是如此。
And the same of course, for blue and for green.
所以在蓝色中，蓝色通道最大为 255，
So in blue, the blue channel is at a maximum of 255,
另一个是零并且是绿色的，
and the other one's at zero and in green,
绿色的情况基本相同。
basically the same happens for green.
接下来我们有白色。
Next up we have white.
在白色中，我们拥有所有三种颜色
And in white, we have all the three colors
最大为 255。
at the maximum of 255.
所以基本上所有颜色都最多
So basically having all the colors at maximum
在另一端给我们一个完整的白色
gives us a complete white while at the other end
光谱中，当我们所有的颜色都为零时，
of the spectrum, when we have all the colors at zero,
我们得到一个完整的黑色。
we get a complete black color.
最后，我们这里的其他三种颜色
Finally, the other three colors that we have here
是其他两种颜色的混合，它们是由它们制成的。
are a mix of the other two colors that they are made of.
所以你会看到这里的洋红色是红色和蓝色的
So you'll see that this magenta here is red and blue
最大，根本没有绿色。
at the maximum and no green at all.
然后我们有这个我认为被称为青色或青色的颜色，
Then we have this I think is called cyan or cyan color,
它在零处有红色，在最大值处有 GNB。
which has a red at zero and GNB at its maximum.
最后黄色的蓝色为零
And finally yellow has blue at zero
另外两个是255。
and the other two at 255.
伟大的。
Great.
所以我希望这是有道理的。
So I hope that this makes sense.
现在我们有了基本的了解
And now that we have a basic understanding
RGB 模型的工作原理，
of how the RGB model works,
让我们实际看看我们如何代表
let's actually see how we can represent
或者我们如何在 CSS 中定义颜色。
or how we can define colors in CSS.
所以在 CSS 中，我们有两种写颜色的方法
So in CSS, we have two ways of writing colors
使用 RGB 模型。
using the RGB model.
这些是 RGB 表示法和十六进制表示法。
And those are the RGB notation and hexadecimal notation.
因此，通过使用 RGB 表示法，
So by using the RGB notation,
我们所做的就是在 CSS 中使用这个 RGB 函数，
all we do is to use this RGB function in CSS,
然后我们简单地为每个指定值
and then we simply specify the values for each
三个颜色通道，红色，绿色和蓝色。
of the three color channels, red, green, and blue.
例如，
So for example,
如果我们将绿色和蓝色设置为最大值，
if we set green and blue to the maximum values,
然后我们得到这个青色，就像我们看到的一样
then we get this cyan color just as we saw
在最后一张幻灯片中。
in the last slide.
另一个例子，这是一个更真实的世界，
00:03:50,120--> 00:03:52,920
这是橙色吗？
Another example, which is a lot more real world,
is this orange color right here.
所以这里是每个频道的数字
So here are the numbers for each channel
看起来更随意一点。
look a little bit more random.
所以这就是我们如何获得真实的颜色
And so this is how we get a real looking color
使用 CSS 并使用 RGB 表示法。
using CSS and using the RGB notation.
那么除了正常的RGB功能外，
Then besides the normal RGB function,
还有具有透明度的RGB。
there is also RGB with transparency.
透明度也称为alpha。
And transparency is also called alpha.
这就是为什么这个函数被称为 RGBA。
And so that's why this function is called RGBA.
所以在这里我们可以指定第四个值，
So here we can specify a fourth value,
在这种情况下是 0.3，
which in this case is the 0.3,
然后这将使这种颜色具有透明度
and this will then give this color a transparency
正如我们在这里看到的。
as we can see here.
看看这个另一个例子，如果我们，例如定义
Looking at this other example, if we, for example define
alpha 值为 0.7，
an alpha value of 0.7,
然后我们看到这个颜色实际上是透明的
then we see that this color is actually transparent
当我们把它放在另一种颜色上时可见
as visible when we put it on top of another color
就像这个绿色广场。
like this green square.
现在，当然我们不必手动上来
Now, of course we don't have to manually come up
这些颜色的这些数字。
with these numbers for these colors.
好的。
Okay.
所以我们不必像手动写244、179、63
So we don't have to like manually write 244, 179, 63
为了得到这个橙子。
in order to get this orange.
所以通常我们只是从某个地方复制某种颜色，
So usually we just copy a certain color from somewhere,
或者我们也可以在 VS 代码中使用颜色选择器生成它。
or we can also generate it with a color picker in VS code.
这样就会自动给我们这些数字。
And so that will then automatically give us these numbers.
但这一切仍然非常重要，让你知道
But all this is still very important so that you know
这些数字实际上意味着什么。
what these numbers actually mean.
好的。但继续前进，
Okay. But moving on,
现在让我们谈谈十六进制表示法，
let's now talk about the hexadecimal notation,
这实际上在 CSS 中使用得更多。
which is actually a bit more used in CSS.
所以这里用十六进制表示法，
So here in the hexadecimal notation,
我们不使用从零到 255 的刻度，
we don't use a scale from zero to 255,
但我们使用从零到 FF 的比例。
but instead we use a scale from zero to FF.
而且FF基本和255一样，
And FF is basically the same as 255,
但以十六进制表示。
but in a hexadecimal scale.
我们不需要深入研究这实际上意味着什么，
And we don't need to go into what that actually means,
但基本上是十六进制数
but basically hexadecimal numbers
不要从零到九，而是从零到十五。
do not go from zero to nine, but from zero to 15.
所以有 16 个不同的数字，而不仅仅是 10 个，
So there are 16 different numbers and not just 10,
最后一个 F。
and the last one F.
这就是为什么这里的 FF 意味着 255。
And so that's why FF here means 255.
现在把它翻译成 CSS，
Now translating that to CSS,
我们像这样写十六进制表示法，
we write hexadecimal notation like this,
使用哈希值，然后是红色、绿色和蓝色的值，
with the hash then the value for red, green, and blue,
就像我在这个屏幕上看到的一样。
just as I have it here on this screen.
所以这当然给了我们
And so this then gives us, of course
与 RGB 符号完全相同的数字。
the exact same number as with the RGB notation.
当然也可以这样做
And the same can of course be done
使用我在这里的橙色示例颜色。
with this orange example color that I have down here.
所以我们可以表示为使用 F4B33F。
So we can represent as using F4B33F.
再一次，这看起来有点随机
And again, this looks kind of random
所以我们通常只是从颜色选择器中复制我们
and so we usually just copy us from the color picker
在 VS 代码中。
in VS code.
现在以十六进制表示，
Now in hexadecimal notation,
还有一种叫做速记的东西，
there's also something called the shorthand,
当所有颜色都是相同的对时，我们可以使用它。
which we can use when all the colors are identical pairs.
所以在我们的青色中，我们有两个零，两个 F，
So in our cyan color here, we have two zeros, two Fs,
再一次，两个F。
and again, two Fs.
所以我们可以把债务缩写成我们的速记
And so we can abbreviate debt into our shorthand
写 0FF。
writing 0FF.
好的。
All right.
现在谈谈我们实际上是如何做事的
And now a little bit about how we actually do things
在现实世界的实践中。
in practice in the real world.
所以在实践中，我们大多使用十六进制表示法，
So in practice, we mostly use the hexadecimal notation,
然后如果我们需要透明度，我们使用 RGBA 函数。
and then if we need transparency, we use the RGBA function.
因此，正如您在左侧看到的 alpha 值。
So as you see here on the left side with the alpha value.
最后，关于恩典，
Finally, just something about grace,
这是一种特殊的颜色
which are a special kind of color
我们在 CSS 中一直需要。
that we need all the time in CSS.
所以基本上在RGB模型中，
So basically in the RGB model,
当三个通道中的三种颜色
when the three colors in the three channels
完全一样，我们得到的是灰色。
are exactly the same, what we get is a gray color.
所以在光谱的两个极端，
So at both extremes of the spectrum,
当所有值都为零时，我们得到完全黑色，
when all of the values are zero, we get complete black,
当它们都处于最大值时，所以在 205 处，
and when all of them are at maximum, so at 205,
或在FF，然后我们得到白色。
or at FF then we get white.
但当然还有很多其他的灰色
But of course there are many other gray colors
在这之间我们可以使用。
in between that we can use.
准确地说，
And to be precise,
正好有 256 种纯灰色可供选择。
there are exactly 256 pure grays to choose from.
例如，其中之一就是这个。
And one of them is this one, for example.
所以红色、绿色和蓝色都是 69。
So where red, green, and blue are all at 69.
所以这给了我们这种漂亮的灰色，
So this gives us this nice gray color,
它的十六进制代码为 444444
which has the hexadecimal code of 444444
在简写符号中可以写成 444。
which in the shorthand notation can be written as just 444.
所以这个，我喜欢用很多的文字颜色。
So this one, I like to use a lot for text color.
当然，让我们看另一个例子。
And of course, let's take a look at another example.
而这个所有值都为 183 的，
And this one that has all the values at 183,
它可以表示为B7B7B7。
and it can be represented as B7B7B7.
所以用十六进制表示
So in the hexadecimal notation
你会再次看到这里的三对
you will see once again that the three pairs here
完全一样。
are exactly the same.
这就是我们实际上拥有的死信号，
And so this is the signal dead we have in fact,
灰色。
a gray color.
好的。
Okay.
所以现在我们对颜色理论有了一点了解
So now that we know a little bit about the theory of color
在代码中，尤其是在 CSS 代码中，
in code and in CSS code in particular,
现在让我们快速学习几个 CSS 属性
let's now quickly learn a couple of CSS properties
我们可以在实践中实际使用颜色。
where we can actually use colors in practice.
以及最简单的需要颜色值的 CSS 属性
And the most simple CSS property that requires a color value
只是颜色属性，
is simply the color property,
我们之前实际上已经使用过。
which we actually already used before.
所以假设我们希望这里的 H1 有
So let's say that we want this H1 here to have
不同的颜色。
a different color.
所以让我们说颜色，
So let's say color,
然后我将在这里指定一些蓝色。
and then I will just specify some blue color here.
1098 和广告。
1098 and ad.
所以这给了我们这种漂亮的蓝色。
And so this gives us this nice blue color.
所以正如我们刚刚学到的，
So as we just learned,
我们在红色通道中有 10 个或 1 个零，
we have 10 or one zero in the red channel,
绿色通道为 98，蓝色通道为广告。
98 in the green channel and ad in the blue channel.
现在，正如我之前提到的，
Now, as I mentioned before,
我们通常使用 VS 代码颜色选择器。
we usually use a the VS code color picker.
所以我们只需将鼠标悬停在一种颜色上即可，
So we get that by simply hovering over a color,
然后从这里，我们可以选择任何颜色
and then from here, we can choose like any color
我们想要的。
that we want.
对？
Right?
所以我们可以把这里的颜色改成别的。
So we can change the color here to something else.
所以这个灰色阴影，然后在那里，
So this shade of gray, and then in there,
我们基本上可以定义灰色应该有多深。
we can basically define how dark that gray should be.
此外，如果我们点击顶部的此处，
Also if we click here at the top,
所以在这里的这个值，这将改变符号。
so in this value here, that will change the notation.
所以现在我们有了这个 HSL，
So now we have this HSL,
我们实际上并没有谈论，
which we actually didn't talk about,
但是如果我们再次点击，我们得到了 RGB。
but then if we click again, we got the RGB.
所以这和以前的颜色完全一样，
And so this is exactly the same color as before,
但使用RGB功能。
but using the RGB function.
对？
Right?
所以让我保存它。
So let me save it.
现在你会看到我们有这个绿色。
And now you'll see that we have this green color.
因此，如果我们再次将其悬停，我们将返回颜色选择器。
So if we hover it again, we get back to the color picker.
现在这个实际上是滑块
And now this one here is actually the slider
为 alpha 值。
for the alpha value.
所以如果我们开始把它往下拉，
So if we start dragging it down,
然后您会看到它自动更改为RGBA。
then you see that automatically it gets changed to RGBA.
好的？
Okay?
然后我们可以在这里定义 alpha 值。
And then here we can, as I mentioned define the alpha value.
所以它实际上已经被保存了，
So it actually already got saved,
你看到现在颜色有点透明了。
and you see that now the color is kind of transparent.
对？
Right?
如果我们把它甚至接近于零，
And if we put it even down close to zero,
然后现在它几乎完全消失了。
then now it's almost completely faded out.
好的。
All right.
这就是我们使用颜色选择器的方式，
So this is how we work with the color picker,
但现在让我们回到我们原来的颜色。
but now let's actually go back to the color that we had.
所以1098ad。
So 1098ad.
好的。
All right.
实际上，我想向您展示另一个不错的技巧，
Actually another nice trick that I wanted to show you,
所以如果你只想要颜色选择器，
so if you just want the color picker,
您可以先指定任何颜色，例如白色，
you can just specify any color first, for example, white,
通过使用 FFF，然后您只需将颜色悬停
by using FFF, and then you just hovered the color
然后你进入颜色选择器。
and then you get to the color picker.
好的。
All right.
所以如果你想要它，例如，这个粉红色，
So if you want it, for example, this pink,
你可以在这里选择，也许有一些阿尔法
you can choose that here, maybe with some alpha
你去吧。
and there you go.
现在它应用了这种粉红色，
And now it applied this pink color,
因为当我们有两个相同的定义时，
because when we have two same definitions,
它只会使用最后一个。
it will simply use the last one.
但是，稍后再谈。
But again, more about that a bit later.
所以让我们摆脱它。
So let's get rid of that.
现在我们实际上也想要 h2 和 h3
And now we actually also want the h2 and the h3
具有完全相同的颜色。
with the exact same color.
所以这个和这个。
So this one and this one.
那么我们应该怎么做呢？
So how should we do that?
我们是否应该在这里简单地复制这个属性
Should we simply copied this property here
到这个声明，然后在这里和这里粘贴它？
to this declaration and then paste it here and here?
好吧，不是真的，对吧？
Well, not really, right?
因为那样我们就会有完全相同的代码
Because then we would have the exact same code
在多个地方。
in multiple places.
这绝不是一个好主意，因为想象一下，
And that is never a good idea, because imagine that,
然后我们想更改颜色，例如更改为橙色。
then we wanted to change the color, for example to orange.
然后我们将不得不通过
Then we would have to go through
所有三种颜色定义并在那里更改它们。
all the three color definitions and change them there.
所以一一改变。
So change them one by one.
当然，这不是我们想要的。
And of course that's not what we want.
因此，我们可以定义一个选择器列表，
So instead, we can define a list of selectors,
就像我们在这里做的一样。
just like we did here.
但现在只有我们想要的
But now only with the ones that we want
蓝领申请。
the blue collar to apply to.
所以这是h1，h2，h3
So that's h1, h2, h3
现在让我们简单地抓取它并粘贴到这里，
and now let's simply grab that and paste it here,
给它一个保险箱，然后就可以了。
give it a safe and there you go.
所以现在 h1、h2 和 h3 具有这种蓝色。
So now the h1, h2, and h3 have this blue color.
而现在，正如你可能已经注意到的那样，
And now, as you also might've noticed one more time,
我们现在还有另一个应用于 h1 的选择器。
we have now yet another selector that is applying to the h1.
所以我们有这个，这个和这个，
So we have this one and this one and this one,
事实上，他们所有的风格
and in fact, all the styles of all of them
现在正在应用于此元素。
are now applying to this element.
接下来，让我们也为文本的其余部分定义一种颜色。
Next up, let's also define a color for the rest of the text.
所以现在剩下的文字完全是黑色的，
So right now the rest of the text is completely black,
但是让我们用我给你看的那个灰色
but let's use that gray color that I showed you
在其中一张幻灯片中。
in one of the slides.
实际上，让我们在这里这样做。
And actually let's do that here.
所以我们希望这篇文章基本上适用于一切，
So we want this text to apply to everything basically,
即使这些在这里，颜色也会被覆盖
even these here and the color will then get overwritten
之后。
later.
再一次，我们将了解为什么
And again, we will learn about why
以及如何在单独的讲座中进行。
and how that works in a separate lecture.
所以记住灰色，
So remember for a gray color,
它需要在所有三个通道中具有相同的值。
it needs to have the same values in all three channels.
比如说 444444，像这样，
And so let's say 444444, like this,
如果你记得速记，
and if you'll remember the shorthand,
那么我们可以进一步缩写它。
then we can abbreviate this even more.
因为每一对都是相同的值
Because each of the pairs is the same value
一如既往只有44岁，
as always just 44,
所以我们可以像这样让它更短。
and so we can make this even shorter just like this.
给它一个保险箱，
Give it a safe,
现在确实，这里所有的文字都是灰色的，
and now indeed, all of this text here is a this gray color,
除了h1，二和三，
except for the h1, two and three,
稍后在这里被覆盖。
which are overwritten here a little bit later.
伟大的。
Great.
所以现在让我们谈谈另一个 CSS 属性
So let's now talk about another CSS property
可以接受颜色值，
that can accept a color value,
这就是背景颜色属性。
and that is the background color property.
所以现在让我们给出我们的主页标题
So let's now give our main page header
略带灰色的背景颜色以使其有点区分
a slight gray background color to distinguish it a bit
从其余的内容。
from the rest of the content.
那么我们怎么能这样做呢？
So how could we do that?
让我们一路下来。
Let's come all the way down here.
而首先想到的
And the first thing that comes to mind
是简单地选择这样的标题，对吗？
is to simply select header like this, right?
所以这里有一个叫做背景颜色的新属性。
And so here is that new property called background color.
在这里让我们使用另一种漂亮的灰色，
And here let's use another nice gray color,
这是F7F7F7。
which is F7F7F7.
所以再一次，你可以看到三种颜色中的颜色，
So again, you can see that the colors in the three colors,
所以三个主要的RGB通道是完全一样的。
so the three main RGB channels are exactly the same.
顺便说一句，在颜色选择器中，
And by the way, here in the color picker,
无论你在这个颜色滑块中是什么颜色
no matter what color you're in here in this color slider
左边总是有这种灰色阴影。
here on the left there is always this shade of grays.
所以如果你从顶部开始，
So if you start here from the top,
您会看到我在这张幻灯片中向您展示的白色。
you see the white that I showed you in this slide.
在最顶端，你会变成黑色。
And at the very top, you get then to black.
好的？
Okay?
所以你总是可以得到灰色
So you can always get a gray color
如果您将滑块移动到非常极端的位置
if you move the slider here at the very extreme
这里的左边。
of this left side here.
但是现在让我们转到F7F7，它是一种颜色，
But now let's go to F7F7, which is a color,
这很容易记住并且很好用。
which is nice to memorize and nice to use.
如此微妙的灰色，也许你甚至看不到这里，
So very subtle gray, maybe you cannot even see it here,
但希望你能在屏幕上看到它。
but hopefully you will see it on your screen.
现在，这里的问题不仅是，
Now, the problem here is that not only,
我们的页眉是灰色的，
our page header got the gray color,
还有这个其他标题。
but also this other header.
所以也许你可以看到它的到来。
So maybe you could see that coming.
所以解决这个问题的方法是给这个标题一个名字
And so the solution to that is to give this header a name
然后仅设置此标题的样式。
and then style only this header.
现在只有这个我们想要设置样式的标题，
Now there's only this one header that we want to style,
所以我们可以在这里使用一个ID，
and so we could use an ID here,
但考虑到我在上一节课中的解释，
but given what I explained in the last lecture,
我们不要那样做，那只是使用一个类。
let's not do that, and that's simply use a class.
我们称之为主标题。
Let's call it main header.
让我复制一下
Let me copy it
并将此标头替换为主标头类。
and replace this header with the main header class.
事实上，现在只有这里的这个人得到了这种灰色。
And indeed now only this one here got this gray color.
让我们摆脱这个测试。
Let's just get rid of this test.
现在我们开始。
And here we go.
好的。
Nice.
如果你真的看不到这个背景颜色，
And if you can't really see this background color,
然后只需使用您的颜色选择器
then just use your color picker
只是使用其他一些灰色阴影。
to just use some other shade of gray.
好的。
All right.
这个视频已经播放了很长时间，
And this video is already running quite long,
但我们还是在这里谈谈另一个属性，
but let's still talk about another property here,
这是关于边界的。
which is about borders.
所以我接下来要做的是添加一些边框
So what I want to do next is to add some border
到这里的这些相关帖子。
to these related posts here.
所以基本上让它们现在看起来像这样。
So basically to make them now look something like this.
好的？
All right?
所以我们在底部和顶部，
So we have at the bottom and at the top here,
这个蓝色边框。
this blue border.
所以这根本不难做到。
So that's not hard to do at all.
所以让我们看看这里的元素是什么。
So let's just see what's the element here.
就是这张幻灯片。
And it is this slide.
所以让我们在这里选择它
So let's just select it here
使用这个元素选择器。
using this element selector.
所以元素选择器基本上就是当我们简单的使用名字的时候
So element selector is basically when we simply use the name
的元素来选择它。
of the element to select it.
好的？
Okay?
所以今年是带点的类选择器。
So this year is the class selector with a dot.
这是带有哈希的 ID 选择器。
This is the ID selector with the hash.
而当我们简单地使用元素的名称时，
And when we simply use the name of the element,
我们称之为元素选择器。
we call that the element selector.
现在让我们开始实际上给它相同的
Now let's start by actually giving it the same
背景颜色。
background color.
所以背景颜色
So background color
然后我们使用之前使用的那个。
and then we use the one that we used before.
VS 代码在这里其实很有帮助
And VS code is actually very helpful here
因为它会扫描 CSS 文档中的文件
because it scans the CSS document for the files
我们已经在使用
that we're already using
这样我们就可以很容易地使用相同的。
so that we can very easily use the same ones.
然后在这里，让我们现在谈谈边界。
And then here, let's now talk about the border.
所以边界，
So border,
现在在这个属性实际上是一个特殊的属性
and now at this property is actually a special property
因为它接受多个值。
because it accepts multiple values.
所以让我们将边框的宽度定义为五个像素，
So let's define the width of the border as five pixels,
边框的样式为实心，
the style of the border as solid,
然后边框的颜色为，
and then the color of the border as,
我们之前已经使用过的颜色，所以这个蓝色。
that color that we already use before, so this blue.
好的？
Okay?
让我们给它一个保险箱
Let's just give it a safe
然后我再解释一下
and then I will explain a little bit more
为什么它会这样工作。
why it works this way.
事实上，这里都是蓝色边框。
And indeed here is all blue border.
美丽的。
Beautiful.
所以回到这个边界属性，
So going back here to this border property,
这实际上是一种特殊的属性。
this is actually a special kind of property.
所以它被称为速记属性，因为
So it's called a shorthand property because
我们可以只使用一个属性
we can just use one property
用于定义三个不同的属性。
for defining three different properties.
所以我们也可以单独设置边框宽度，
So we could also individually style the border width,
边框样式和边框颜色属性。
border style and border color properties.
但通常我们一口气做完
But usually we do it all in one run
并简单地同时定义所有内容。
and simply define everything at the same time.
现在在这里，您可以定义很多不同的关键字。
Now here, you can define a lot of different keywords.
例如，dotted 总是一种可能性。
For example, dotted is always a possibility.
所以这看起来像这样。
So this will look something like this.
您也可以使用虚线，它看起来像这样。
You can use dashed as well, which will look like this.
但通常我从不使用这些。我总是追求固体。
But usually I never used those. I always go for solid.
好的。
Okay.
所以这给了我们整个边界
So this it gives us the entire border
围绕整个元素。
around the entire element.
但是，我们只想要顶部和底部的边框。
However, we only want the border at the top and the bottom.
所以不是像这样定义边界属性，
And so instead of defining the border property like this,
此属性也有特殊的变体。
there are also special variants of this property.
所以我们也可以说边界顶部。
So we can also say border top.
所以，正如你所料，
And so this, as you might expect,
我们只会在元素的顶部设置边框样式。
we'll only style the border at the top side of the element.
所以就像这样。
So just like this.
好的？
Okay?
然后让我们选择所有这些并粘贴到这里
Then let's select all of this and paste it here
因为我们还想要底部的边框。
because we also want the border at the bottom.
如此简单的边框底部。
So easy enough border bottom.
给它一个保险箱，我们开始吧。
Give it a safe, and here we go.
只是为了完整起见，
And just for the sake of completeness,
我们也可以说左边界和右边界。
we can also say border left and border right.
然后我们将回到第一方
And so then we will be back to square one
我们在所有四个方面都有边界。
where we have the borders on all the four sides.
所以当然，这没有意义
And so of course, this doesn't make sense
那么我们将简单地使用边界属性。
then we would simply use the border property.
这些我们无论如何都不想要。
These ones we don't want anyway.
所以我们回到了这个结果。
And so we are back to this result.
好的。
All right.
这就是我们在 CSS 中使用颜色的方式。
And this is how we work with colors in CSS.
现在让我快速提一下，我们也可以使用
Now let me just quickly mention that we can also use
这些预定义的颜色名称就像我们所做的一样
these predefined color names just as we did
一开始是蓝色的。
in the very beginning with the color of blue.
这么快就给你看。
So quickly show that to you.
假设我们要设置背景颜色
So let's say that we wanted to set a background color
对于整个网页。
for the entire webpage.
所以这也可以通过添加样式来实现
So that's also possible simply by adding a style
到身体。
to the body.
所以我们可以像这样做背景颜色，
So we can just do background color like this,
在这里我们可以指定这些名称之一。
and here we can specify one of these names.
所以如果我给它一个保险箱，
So if I give it a safe,
那么一切都有这种非常美丽的蓝色
then everything has this very beautiful blue color
作为背景。
as the background.
当然除了我们特别给出的元素
Except of course the elements that we specifically gave
另一种背景颜色。
another background color.
对？
Right?
或者我们可以使用其他东西。
Or we could use something else.
所以通常如果你刚开始写一些颜色名称，
So usually if you just start writing some color name,
你会从 VS 代码中得到很多建议
you will get a lot of suggestions here from VS code
然后你可以像这样选择其中一个。
and then you can select one of them like this.
好的？
Okay?
但我们当然不希望这样
But of course we don't want that
所以让我们通过点击注释来注释掉这段代码
So let's just comment out this code by hitting comment
或控制斜线，然后我们就恢复正常了。
or control slash, and then we are back to normal.
好的。
Okay.
现在，只是为了巩固这些知识，
And now, just to consolidate this knowledge a little bit,
我建议你尝试这三个属性
I suggest you to experiment with these three properties
我们刚刚学到的。
that we just learned.
例如，通过为更多元素添加边框，
For example, by adding borders to some more elements,
比如一些标题或一些列表，
like some headings or some lists,
并且还更改了更多的文本颜色
and also changing some more text colors
尤其重要的是玩
and especially important would also be to play around
用你自己的颜色选择器一点点。
with the color picker a little bit on your own.
所以只需花 10 或 15 分钟即可完成
So just take 10 or 15 minutes to do that
然后我会在下一个视频中见到你。
and then I see you in the next video.